Hansraj Das

Software Engineer at Google via Globallogic

G-318, Mangolpuri, 110083, New Delhi, Delhi India

in hansrajdas 🖸 hansrajdas



Seasoned software engineer with extensive experience in software/web development, testing and maintenance of complex products. Most of the work experience revolve around Python, C/C++ and Golang. Good understanding of databases - MySQL, SQLite and LDAP. In depth understanding of algorithms, data structures, time/space complexity and OOPs concepts. Also have hands on experience in front end frameworks/libraries - AngularJS and jQuery. Currently working as a developer for Google as TVC @Google Gurgaon, India.

SKILLS

Languages Master	Languages Intermediate	Framework Intermediate
python c/c++ shell scripting	golang javascript css html	angularjs jquery sqlalchemy webapp2
Databases Master	Software Tools Master	Server Master
mysql ldap	vim wireshark gdb valgrind callgrind purify bullseye jenkins	apache socket programming
Version Control Master	Operating System Master	Cloud Platform Tools Intermediate
git cvs svn	ubuntu unix linux windows	google appengine(gae) google cloud sql kubernetes

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at GlobalLogic **March 2017- Current** https://globallogic.com

Working on 2 projects at Google, gurgaon

- A web based tool used to maintain each vendors work profile at google. Technology stack used is python, angularJS and coludSQL
- Another project is used to create and target announcements to specific vendors. Technology stack used is golang, jQuery, cloudSQL and google appengine
- Extensively used google app engine and kubernetes for deployment and management of softwares

Technical Leader at Aricent, Gurgaon October 2011- March 2017

https://www.aricent.com/

Majorly involved in development of HSS REST interface and LTE EPC

- Developed XML based REST interface to configure LTE HSS using python, C/C++, gSoap and apache web server
- Developed support for distributed HSS in EMS, EMS is a web based tool to configure LTE EPC nodes. Technologies used is python, C/C++, javascript and HTML
- Developed a python based tool to migrate routing configurations stored at Idap server (in Idif files) on new hardware platform
- Developed S6a and STa interface in HSS, in depth knowledge of diameter protocol
- Integrated all LTE EPC core network nodes (MME, SGW, PGW, HSS and PCRF)

EDUCATION

B.Tech Electronics and Communication at Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering **2007 - 2011**

Grade: 73.4%

XII at Kendriya Vidyalaya, Rohini, Delhi

2006 - 2007

Grade: 86.4%

X at Kendriya Vidyalaya, Rohini, Delhi

2004 - 2005

Grade: 65.8%

AWARDS

Individual Excellence Award at Globallogic

Got individual excellence award for quarter Jan-Mar 2018

Aricent Training Project at Aricent

Won second prize for training project (network firewall) at aricent, Jan 2012

Chess Competition at Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering

2nd Place in Chess Competition | Annual Sports Meet 2009-2010

LANGUAGES

HindiNative speaker (mother tongue) English Native speaker

REFERENCES

"Hansraj has very good technical skills. He worked with me in a complex HSS feature development. He has shown great character and problem solving skills during that assignment. He is someone you can trust and rely on. He is very soft spoken and a good listener. I will definitely recommend him for his attitude and technical competence. And would look for a chance to work again with him. All the very best. Cheers!!"

LinkedIn Recommendation - Yashveer Arya, Engineering Project Manager at Aricent

"I have worked with Hansraj, he is an excellent team player and highly productive in his all assignments. He works proactively and his presence gives confidence to the team members. He has collaborated with other teams (HSS and IMSLite) for fixing their module issues by providing necessary logs and detailed analysis of issues, showing his flexibility to take on new challenges. His "never say no attitude" differentiates him from others and that's the reason he commands a great rapport in his team. Keep it up Hansraj:)"

LinkedIn Recommendation - Rahul Tiwari, Engineering Project Manager at Aricent